So today's focus will be
very much on improving
the models using search.
And there can be two kinds
of search that we will see.
One in code models, where
we are sampling a lot
and then we are searching based
on that, and then deep research
style search, which you
will see in homework three.
So a lot of what we
will cover in AlphaCode
and AlphaCode 2,
those search patterns
you will use also in homework.
Your homework two is
focused on human eval,
so this will give
you an overview
of what to expect
in simpler problems
and then even more
complex problems.
And then the agent
search, this will
be closer to what we will
give you in homework three.
The broad thing that I want
to say with these models
is that we know that the
solutions lie in the search
space of the models, but how
do you curate the answer out
of the search space of what
the model outputs is roughly
what we are covering today.
So let's start with AlphaCode.
So the problem we
want to solve here
is a more complex version of
the simple coding agent problem.
So if you use a coding
agent, what you often get
is some form of an autocomplete,
where you have a line,
and then the coding agent will
complete the line for you.
So this is closer to a
competitive programming problem,
where given a competitive
programming problem,
you're given a
problem description
and then you're given
some input and outputs,
so you have some a contract in
that programming problem, which
says that if you give
this set of inputs,
you should get this
set of outputs.
And what you want
to really solve for
is how do we solve these
competitive programming problems
so that--
so the things that
we already are
able to do as code
completions, but when
we try to do blocks of
code, or solve real problems
end-to-end, that starts to
be a much harder problem,
as you'll see in the ways
that this problem gets solved.
So just to give you a preview
of how AlphaCode came about
and what it achieved, and it
was-- this is an older paper,
but it's worth remembering
that at that point in time,
when AlphaCode was released,
which is almost four years ago,
it ranked top 54% among
the contest participants
in 10 contests, and
this was the first time
it was shown that
AI can generalize
beyond just narrow tasks and
solve problems end-to-end.
And this was a
much harder problem
than what you can do in just
human eval, where you basically
are given a very small problem
like complete this function,
or you're given instructions
to exactly solve
what you want to
solve, and you don't
have to reason about,
understanding the problem
and then figuring out what it
would take to solve the problem.
So this was definitely
longer problem descriptions,
longer solution
lengths, and you were
having to understand
from the docstring, what
is the right solution approach
even before going and solving
that?
So it's not just like taking
the problem description
from the programmer and
then just coding it up.
And this is well understood that
when the models are generating
suggestions in one single
line, it's much easier for us
as software developers
to interact with that,
and you get much higher
success rates, for example,
in Copilot and
equivalent functions,
but when you have to
solve problems end-to-end,
that ends up being a
much harder problem.
And I'll go through each of
these block diagrams one by one.
This is pre having large
models, so they actually
were pre-training
their own models.
The pre-trained models in the
next report will get replaced,
so what you see here is that
you have a stage, where you are
basically coming up with
a model from which you
are going to sample.
Now this model we will later
replace with a large language
model.
So here, they're also doing
pre-training and fine tuning.
And the data that fed that data
that really helped this model
train was GitHub data
and then code contests.
What code contest is
basically a large chunk
of problems and
solutions that come
from competitive programming.
So once they trained
the model here,
they're going to sample
a lot of solutions.
So we have seen repeated
sampling before,
so this is repeated sampling,
but at a massive scale,
so you will end up with
a lot of solutions.
And then you're going to play
some tricks to figure out
which set of solutions
should we even run tests on?
So, so far, we've just been
closing the loop, where
we take whatever set of
solutions the model outputs
and then running tests on them.
In this particular case, you're
actually going to select,
so there's a selection
stage before you're
going to complete and
execute and evaluate.
So just to walk through
things step-by-step.
And so the first
step is pre-training.
You're going to
pre-train a model.
In this particular case, they're
going to use masked language
model loss.
You can also have a decoder only
model, which we'll see shortly,
and the model is
trained on GitHub code
about 700 gigabytes
of that trained
with next token prediction.
What's interesting is that
when they fine tune it,
they are using some tricks, so
they're using regularization
so that they can assign
higher probability
to more meaningful patterns.
This is interesting in code.
And then they're doing something
called as value conditioning
and prediction.
So the thing that I want
to highlight in this slide
is that in the
regularization technique,
when they're doing fine tuning,
they assign higher weight
to higher likelihood
tokens so that there
are certain tokens that
will have higher likelihood,
and then they are putting lower
weight to lower likelihood
tokens, so this
is called as GOLD,
so it will help
improve the precision.
So in the next token
prediction loss,
they are basically adding
a weighting mechanism
to take into account the
likelihood of the tokens also,
which helps in
certain ways and helps
to assign high probabilities
to more meaningful patterns,
so this is done in
the fine tuning phase.
So once you get this
model that is able to--
and this was an encoder, decoder
model that they were initially
using, and then they also
tried with decoder only models
in AlphaCode 2.
Once they get this
model, they are going
to try large scale sampling.
They generate 1 million.
1 million is a large number.
They generate 1 million diverse
sample programs per question,
so if you have a question,
a competitive programming
question, they're generating
1 million solutions,
half in Python, half in C++,
so machines can do that.
And they randomize the
problem tags and the ratings
in the prompt, and they use
a high sampling temperature,
so it's like the solutions
are going to be diverse.
And once they generate these
solutions, what they're doing
is they are doing some amount
of filtering and clustering.
So they filter the samples to
only those that passed tests
given in the problem
statement, and then they
are clustering them so that
they're syntactically different,
but semantically equivalent, so
they differentiate between that.
So they are basically using
a clustering mechanism,
where they use a separate
test input generation model,
train it to predict test inputs
given problem descriptions,
and then create these new test
inputs for unseen problems,
so they're basically
trying to figure out
different tricks to
cluster this test inputs,
the semantic equivalence
being one way to do that.
Now the reason this
clustering is important
is it is effectively
providing a way for us
to select which set of
solutions are diverse enough
for us to then evaluate
to close the loop.
So now, what you
can do is you can
submit only a
subset of solutions
to the Codeforces platform,
which is the actual competition
platform.
And that will check the
program correctness.
It will benchmark against other
best performers on this task
like human competitors, but
the challenge here is that you
cannot submit all the solutions.
So 1 million solutions cannot
be submitted to this platform,
so they have done
a curation phase,
a filtering and clustering
phase to get to this stage.
And then there's also
evaluation on code contests.
Remember, that code contest
was used to train the model,
so there is a test set
that they hold out,
which will basically
give them a signal.
So this is the data set
that is created by authors,
but they can also measure signal
on this particular data set
to figure out if their solution
is supposed to do well or not.
So when they first
did evaluation
on Codeforces platform, they
took their model, ran it live,
generated samples,
filtered with example test,
cluster to get some
submissions, and then
submitted it to the platform,
and they ran this with--
they submitted in
10 competitions,
which each had
5,000 participants.
And what they found was
that their solutions
with this AlphaCode actually
had an average ranking of 54.3,
assuming 10 submissions per
problem, so not 1 million,
and it was competitive
with 28% of the competitors
in the last six months.
So this table is
showing you that if you
looked at a certain
contest ID, how
was the AlphaCode model doing?
What was its percentage
ranking, the best ranking
and the estimated ranking and
the worst ranking relative
to other programmers?
This is more of a ranking
based as to once you submit
a solution, you're ranked
based on the efficiency
of your solution and the
correctness of your solution.
Before I move
further, questions?
Yes.
You go back to previous page.
It seems like the--
This one?
So numbers.
In the table, if you
look at the performance
across different data
sets, it seems that--
This is different contexts.
It seems they did pretty
well with the final 1623.
Even the worst ones
like 54% and 1618
we see the algorithm
is pretty good.
But if you look at some
others like 1613 and 1615
one is getting worse.
It's getting worse by 20%.
I'm just curious why [INAUDIBLE]
variation of [INAUDIBLE].
I'll ask you that question back.
What do you think?
This is your pipeline.
Where will the
variance come from?
So different contexts will
have different problem inputs.
Maybe it's the two contexts.
So the two context,
they perform well
is the context as
similar as possible.
But there are other
places that [INAUDIBLE]
somewhere in your context
that the algorithm
may fail to or struggle to
answer because it [INAUDIBLE].
The large scale-- so
what's your name, again?
What he's asking is
why do we get variance
across different context IDs,
and it does well in one context
and does not do well in another?
So at the end of
the day, you are
depending on how close are
these say, contest problems?
In distribution, they are.
So that's one
plausible hypothesis.
The other plausible hypothesis
is that our ability to--
so in the large
scale sampling, that
would control like is one
of the solutions correct?
But then our ability to select
the right set of candidate
solutions might also be affected
in different context IDs,
so the selection stage can
also be a bottleneck here.
There can be solutions that
are almost correct, but not
completely correct.
Yes.
So the [INAUDIBLE] example
seems like a very arbitrary one.
Do you have an experiment that
shows how the model possibly
scales as the number of samples?
So I think you're
basically right.
So they do have some
experiments that they did,
but it's order of magnitude.
So with this
particular model size,
and there is some
results I'll show you.
With this particular
model size, they
had to go for much
larger number of samples.
If you remember from earlier
slides on test time compute,
when you have
smaller models, you
do have to go for much
larger number of samples
to get the same pass@k.
For example, here is one
of the saturates, because--
So let's look at the results and
then come back to that comment.
But on the question
around why is it
different in different contexts?
The inputs are
different and then
the pipeline will--
the selection stage can
be a bottleneck, so
both of those influence
where it does well and
where it doesn't do well.
So there is two
things worth noticing.
So when we compute solutions
with repetitive sampling
in test-time compute,
and this is something
that you're definitely
using in homework two,
you have this notion of pass@k.
So that's the
percentage of problems.
So if you get the model
to generate k samples
and you submit all of them for
evaluation on the hidden test,
how many problems will actually
solve the problem description
that was given?
It measures how good is the
search aspect of the sampling
process, so it's basically
coverage in the lectures
that we covered before.
What this particular
benchmark measures is 10@k.
10 being the number
of submissions
that you're going to go
submit for evaluation.
So even if you get the
model to output k samples,
in this particular
case, 1 million,
you don't have the ability
to measure correctness
on all the samples for the
final set of solutions,
so you do have to do some
selection, or scoring
to decide which set of
solutions I'm going to submit.
So it measures also
the filtering process
of how well the
model will behave
when you have a very
large number of samples,
so you're not just
generating samples,
but you have to do
some search yourself
before you can submit the
solutions for evaluation
to hidden tasks.
Now, why does this matter?
So this is validation
set and that's test set.
And they train different model
sizes, so this is 9B model,
41B model, so that's
a larger model,
and then 41B with clustering.
And what they're presenting
is validation set results
for 10@1k, so this is the
question you were asking me.
They're basically going to
submit 10 solutions out of 1k
generated outputs, and then keep
increasing that to 10k, 100k,
and 1 million.
And then they're going
to do similar set
for test set as well.
And what you will notice is
that typically, the larger model
size consistently will do better
than the smaller model size.
That is something we
have talked about before.
But the other thing to
notice is that as you
go for larger number
of samples, which
is something we have seen as
well, you are able to do better.
So going from 10@1k
to 10@1 million,
you're clearly doing better,
and same on the test set side.
And the clustering.
So typically, we had covered
this slide with pass@ number
of samples.
In this particular case, even
clustering is consistently--
so 10@1k will definitely also
improve similar to pass@1k.
And then if you look
at the last row here,
which is 41B plus clustering,
you see that that's consistently
better.
So like 9B, versus 41B,
versus 41B plus clustering.
The 41B plus clustering is
definitely going to still be
better than the one before
because it definitely provides
an improvement.
And the reason for doing
that is because if you
were to measure the
set of solutions
that the model has
output and you wanted
to measure their diversity, the
clustering provides you a way
to submit only the
diverse set of solutions,
if you can only
submit 10 problems.
And since competitive coding
problems are quite difficult,
you don't get much
benefit out of submitting
the same set of solutions
to the evaluation process,
so if you can choose which
set of problems to submit,
that helps.
And if we were to measure just
10@k and pass@k, if you had--
so pass@k would be unlimited
attempts and 10@k would be 10
attempts on evaluating
per problem.
On the x-axis, you have
the sampling budget,
and on the y-axis,
you have this accuracy
in terms of how many attempts
you get to solve the problem.
The solve rate definitely scales
linearly with more samples,
so this is very much in line
with what we had seen for pass@k
in repeated sampling.
So even after the
selection stage,
we definitely see the same log
linear trend with more samples.
And better models have better
slopes, so this particular case,
you see the 41B, which is the
blue curve, has better solve--
Sorry, the purple curve, 41B,
has better slope compared
to the 300 million parameter
model at the bottom,
and same applies
even for pass@k.
And then the final thing is
that when only 10 samples are
submitted, then you do get
bottlenecked in certain ways,
so you can get higher accuracy.
So if you compare the
y-axis 10@k versus pass@k,
if you have unlimited
attempts per problem,
which is a synthetic scenario,
you are almost getting
to something above
40%, and here,
you are only getting to 30%,
so there is definitely some
bottlenecking happening
in selection stage.
So you are bottlenecked by
how you filter and cluster
in some ways, when you have to
choose which set of solutions
will pass the test.
Yes.
I'm just wondering if
this trend continue,
you really got this tool
another six or more.
That would be 1 trillion.
If you really get 1
trillion as the score,
this attracting
demo will be double.
So I think that we really need
to just make it 1 trillion.
We can just double
the performance.
Well, we're going
to AlphaCode 2.
Making the model better is
a slightly easier access
than scaling the number of
samples that you're going after.
So on AlphaCode 2, the
model performance improves,
and that helps you reduce
the number of samples
to get the same performance
or at 1 million,
you'll get a much
better performance.
So this is an older model,
but it's a weaker model.
But the trends generally hold.
And in some ways, there a--
I mean, the larger models have
done better generally speaking,
but there's a model
capability gap.
So if the base models
are not strong enough,
they're going to hit
limits at a certain point.
So the problem is if you really
have no problem with the sample
budget.
So you can really be confident
in the whole purpose,
or you can just really do
one bit of a three example
with this graph.
If the log linear trend
continues then yes.
That might be a project idea
worth exploring if the costs are
not prohibitive.
Yes.
I just want to say
I think that could
be really useful if you think
that one problem is really
important.
You can just forward your--
All you can do is
solving that problem.
According too, yeah.
I think the challenge
for that, which
is something that is worth
also-- that's a good comment.
So one of the challenges
with solving it that way
is that you kind of assume
that if we sample more,
the diversity
continues to increase.
So one of the challenges that
we will see in AlphaGo 2,
and I'll emphasize
again, is that you
do have to ensure that as
you sample more and more,
you are getting more
diverse solutions.
And part of the
process of clustering
is that it's
effectively figuring out
which are the diverse
set of solutions.
So if you sample 10x more
than what was sampled here,
that you don't end up with
more diverse solutions,
then you're actually
not going to improve.
Is there a reason why we have
a log linear relationship here?
Why is it not any other
modeling of y versus x?
So this was covered earlier,
I think the passer k
versus unlimited attempts.
This is theoretically derivable.
And I think the main
thing that I'm emphasizing
is that even after
the selection phase,
that log linear trend holds.
The passer k versus sample
budget, this was covered in--
I don't know the lecture
number, but Azalea
covered this in that paper
actually theoretically derives
it.
This is the large
language monkey's paper
or the one right after that.
Yeah, but if you look
at the derivation,
we can work through
that offline.
OK, So if we look
at takeaways, I
think the fun aspect
here is that we
can get high
coverage by sampling,
and then-- so this large-scale
sampling, this filtering,
and the clustering approach,
you can get higher coverage.
And they were able to
actually also make sure
that the model is not just
copying existing solutions.
It actually reasons.
So they did some search
over the training data
and actually saw that there
was-- the generated code
had some novelty.
So this was actually
generalization out
of distribution.
The challenge with
these particular set
of approaches that they noticed
that's worth highlighting
is that they were training
the model on loss.
And loss is often a poor
proxy for solve rates,
so because there are
many solutions that
could have solved the problem.
So they did see that
this model did not
do well on say, dynamic
programming or constructive
algorithms in some ways.
So it was not the strong
in certain domains.
And then the other aspect
was that it was requiring
a large-scale set of sampling.
So that was not ideal in
terms of how practical this
is to be used everywhere.
If there was a time bound,
then you can imagine.
So if you basically were
just examining accuracy,
then you want to make
unlimited attempts.
But if you want to do
time-limited bound in terms
of efficiency, then you do want
to rank acceptable solutions
as they get generated.
So that becomes
really important.
And as I already mentioned,
the more difficult domains
required more experiments.
So this was not like-- this
solution approach actually
wasn't working well
on difficult problems.
And in fact, there, it's
both a matter of you
might need more steps
to solve the problem.
So this particular
approach in one shot
did not do a
reasonably strong job.
So multi-step solution
approaches would do better here.
So this was AlphaCode summary.
Now, let's see.
What can we do better?
So this was like 2022.
If you look at the next set
of paper which is AlphaCode 2,
they improved upon
this substantially.
And that was really helpful.
And we can also learn
what were the differences.
And that really helps us
understand what pushes
the frontier even further.
So AlphaCode 2 started
with a hypothesis of what
if you don't
pre-train your model?
You use an existing LLM.
So in this particular case,
this work was at Google.
So they decided to use
Gemini Pro instead of using
in training their own model.
And then, they want to customize
it to get a better performance
on this particular problem set
on competitive programming.
So the first set of
changes that were made
were that instead
of pre-training,
you basically are just going
to fine tune Gemini Pro.
So it's not just prompting.
They are fine tuning the model.
And then, in terms of
sampling and evaluation
for the large-scale sampling,
they want to ensure diversity.
So for diversity, they actually
had multiple AlphaGo 2 models
that allow for massive sampling.
So when they did and
go and do fine tuning,
they actually had multiple
variants of this model
so that they get diversity
in the output sampling.
And then the third
thing they did
was that to select the
subset of candidates,
they had a scoring model.
So you can see that
as a reward model,
which was used for obtaining
the best candidates.
So it's not just based on
clustering and filtering,
which is a heuristic
for saying OK, this
would be semantically
equivalent,
but there's diversity in syntax.
They are actually now going
for a scoring function
which can learn that function.
So it's a learned
approximation of what
should be given high score and
what should be given low score.
So the new ideas here,
as I highlighted,
was A, that they are going
to fine-tune a Gemini Pro
model to score correctness
before submitting.
So that's a reward model.
And they also had
a family of models
based on different
hyperparameters,
so different difficulty
levels, different tags.
So they fine-tune several models
with varied hyperparameters,
and then that maximizes
the diversity of the number
of samples they generate.
And they also improve
their data sets.
So the data set that
they fine-tune on
is V2 version of CodeContests,
which is actually open source.
And then, they had
another high-quality data
set for scoring purposes.
So going back to this
diagram, what changes next?
So let's take a
more detailed look.
So here, if you look at the
input model on the fine-tuning
stage, you have
this new data set
called CodeContests V2, which
is going to be used to generate.
Now, you're going
to do some tagging.
So there's some amount just
like, take your CodeContests V2
data set and put--
bisect it or rather segment
it into different data sets
to fine-tune different
versions of models that
are going to generate samples.
So that's one set of
intermediate AlphaCode 2 models
that they will generate.
And then they had
another high-quality data
set they're going to use
to make this even better.
And this same set of
model, same set of data
will also be used to
generate a scoring
model from the same model.
And based on that,
they're going to--
so this is basically
a notion of the zero.
The data set is segmented and
used to tune multiple models
to get more diverse samples.
What's different
about the data set
is that the problems and
solutions are higher quality
and vetted and scored better.
And the scoring model
is able to estimate
the correctness of the
code sample between 0 and 1
based on this higher
quality data set.
So they manually curate it.
This data set got more
human annotators in place
so that they could
train the model
to estimate correctness better.
And then the other
aspect is that they
had this family
of models instead
of having just one model.
Now, on the sampling
and evaluation side,
they split the
sampling across models.
They in fact, went to only C++.
Earlier it was C++ and
Python half samples.
So they split the sampling
across models but only C++.
And when they
generate the samples,
they're randomizing the
temperature and the metadata
so that they can
get diverse outputs.
So this is the massive
sampling pipeline.
For each output, they're going
to execute on test input,
and they are filtering
out anything that's
incorrect or doesn't compile.
So they remove 95%
of the samples.
At this point, they're left
with about 50 case samples.
And then, after that
process, they're
going to aggregate and keep
the top 10 largest clusters.
There's reranking on top of
that based on the scoring model
to say how likely
is it to be correct.
So they score each
code sample and pick
the best candidate per cluster.
And once they have
that, that's when
they're going to
submit and say that did
it win or did it not win?
The eval is going to
be same as AlphaCode.
So if we are to
compare results now,
this is comparing AlphaCode
2 versus AlphaCode.
So AlphaCode-- so on the x-axis,
you see the sampling budget.
AlphaCode, we were
doing 1 million samples.
Here, we are going to vary the
sampling budget per problem.
And on the y-axis,
you have solve rate.
As you can see that, once
you get to 100 samples, you
basically--
so AlphaCode was using
1 million samples.
For AlphaCode 2, once
you get to 100 samples,
you are achieving the same
solve rate as AlphaCode.
And if you want to go beyond
that, you can use more samples.
So the solve rate is still
improving with the increase
in sampling budget.
And if you were
to basically say,
what is the maximum
performance achieved?
AlphaCode 2 with 1
million was solving 43%.
It was getting 43% solve
rate, while AlphaCode was only
getting 25%.
So in this particular
case, even though there
is using the same
number of samples,
a better base model, better
diverse solutions, and then
better scoring is giving them.
So this whole system is
giving them performance gains,
which is almost 2x relative to
where the previous system was.
Questions?
Yes.
95% of sampling wasted on not
compiling or a poor answer
seems like a very high cost.
Were there any
other studies to see
if there could be better
methods of sampling, more
reliable answers, maybe
really better prompting, or--
I mean, it didn't mention
randomized temperature,
but were there any
other approaches?
So in this particular
case, this paper did not.
But if you are to refer
to some of the work
that we have discussed
before, what would
you need to do to improve that?
This is an older
piece of work, right?
Yes.
I would try the approaches
we took in homework 1.
Like?
Like better
prompting or better--
maybe using-- instead
of wasting all
of the compute on
1 million sample,
maybe I would try
to self-iterate
based on one of the sampling
at least once or maybe at least
try to have a better
method of aggregating
some of the information
from the various sampling.
Great.
So I think what you're saying--
so just to repeat the answer,
in homework 1, you had done
some form of self-refinement.
So this is essentially
parallel search, in some ways.
You've generated a
lot of solutions,
and then you are
clustering on top of that.
If you do a refinement
process where
you have generated
some solutions
and then you're saying, OK, if
I can get any feedback on top,
then can I improve
these solutions better?
That's one approach that would
cut down the number of samples,
but increase the time that if
you can collect any feedback.
The question I would ask is that
how would you collect feedback?
Like, what would be feedback
in this particular case?
That's worth thinking through.
I think the other comment would
be that if you can get the model
to do slightly better with
RL, so if it can get better
at solving things
with the RL loop
in between when we cover
train time scaling,
then that can help
cut down how much we
need to put in test time.
So both those
approaches can reduce
the cost on the sampling side.
Let's try that one.
So when it comes to a
practical application--
so when we are using
everyday thinking models
and we are still talking about
a couple of dozens of samples,
I mean when it
comes to time scale,
and when we hear about these
OpenAI authenticate a month's
researcher, those are
the multi thousand, multi
hundreds of case of samples
applied in production.
So I think the way
to look at the system
is more of how you would build
a system that is generating
those dozen of samples.
I think we have
discussed this before.
For us to think
about these systems,
I think the big
question you're asking
is how would you
build the system
to begin with that can reason
well, that can close the loop?
So I think there is a
line of research which has
tried to answer that question.
And what this is covering is
that if you started with an LLM
and you wanted to solve
these complex problems,
how would you build a system
that can solve that problem?
And then, if you can distill
all of that knowledge
into a single model, then that
becomes a large reasoning model.
But this is more of
a multi-agent system
in almost some ways,
where you're basically
having one model produce outputs
and then another model score it.
And then, here a family of
models is producing outputs,
and then there is another family
of models that's scoring it.
So that gives you more tricks
up your sleeve if you had
to re-architect the
system from scratch,
as opposed to depending on what
the current generation of models
can or cannot do.
And the paradigm, I
believe, because at the end
of the day, when we are
saying in test-time compute,
there should be a solution
in this space of what
model outputs
generated, the paradigm
is effectively that you should
be able to search that solution.
So what this is
roughly answering
is how would you search for
a solution in the output
space of what models output?
You still have question?
Yes.
So why is the
scoring model here?
Nothing is a suppose gift.
Say that again.
Why is the scoring model--
I think the value is called--
how am I saying this?
Why is it called--
why is the scoring model
only desired model use?
So I think the way
to look at it is
that why is the scoring model
not using code count as V2?
I mean, you can train your--
so the code counts as V2, there
would be contamination, right?
The scoring model should not
see exactly the same data,
but it does need to see some
data in the distribution, right?
It's basically a matter of
you're training the scoring
model, not necessarily
on the same problems,
but you want this-- if you're
designing that system from
scratch, how would you
train a reward model?
Would you you want to show it is
that for these kind of problems,
if you had these two
solutions, which solution
should you prefer?
That's what you're
teaching the scoring model
or what ranking should
you apply to that?
And if your first train--
well, that is you on budget.
So the first train
is that kind of model
that you have to decide.
Is it the same, for example
the two legal set that it were?
I mean, you could have
mixed those data sets
and then done the
same thing, yes.
But that is a doable exercise.
It's just multi-stage.
It's not the same in
the sense that when
you do any kind of
fine-tuning, if you're
changing the quality,
then the model--
and if you're not mixing
the previous version,
then the model is forgetting
some of the previous information
when it's tuning
in the last stage.
OK?
So if you were to look at the
aggregate results of AlphaCode 2
in terms of the normalized score
versus the how it would compare
to human contestants, there.
And the way you
would do that is you
would basically compare the
percentile of contestants
who score at a certain level.
What AlphaCode two was achieving
is 85th percentile between
the expert and the candidate or
the master candidate solutions,
while the human--
While AlphaCode was
outperforming, 46% AlphaCode 2,
if you took top two performance
on the-- if you took top two
solutions, then it was
actually outperforming 99.5%,
but overall, it was basically
scoring closer to 85th
percentile across
human contestants.
So that was a big deal.
It was like, OK, in this
particular code, these problems
and this competitive
programming,
it's doing very
well in some way.
So that was a big
accomplishment in one
single year just with
an improved system.
And I think, for
us, what's worth
learning here is that we are
increasing the performance
with less number of samples.
So we didn't have to necessarily
scale the number of samples.
But we had better
foundation model.
And then the scoring model that
is selecting the best candidate
is also helping the solution.
The experimentation
is still quite costly.
And then, as one of our
classmates pointed out,
this is very specific to code.
And then a lot of the compute
is wasted in generating samples
that might have bad
syntax and so on that you
have to go and filter out.
So one set of questions
that I have for the class
at this point in time
is that how would
you change these methods based
on task complexity, for example?
So actually, I will
pose that question.
And then the other
question I will
pose is, how can we
embed reasoning directly
into these models?
Take a minute to talk to
folks next to you or somewhere
in the vicinity.
And then let's come back and
discuss those two questions.
Let's tackle the
second question.
So how can we
change these methods
based on task complexity?
So if I have easy problems
versus hard problems.
Any takers for that?
OK.
What you could do is you have a
separate model initially judge
each question based of it.
It would made easy,
medium, or hard.
And you create, like your
data set where you're sampling
from also has those labels.
Then in this, if you declare
a question that's easy,
you sample more
from the easy bank.
So it's a better sample
you can struggle with.
So is it more on
the training side
you will change or is it
more on the sampling side
that you'll make this change?
More on the sampling side.
That's where you will change.
There isn't more-- you
can root any more of this.
OK, so you're saying that if
you have a simple problem, then
you will sample more from--
--the simple problems, yeah.
OK.
So you will-- in
AlphaCode 2 basically,
you will use the
model that's trained
on perhaps simpler problems.
Is that the suggestion?
OK.
Are there ideas?
The solver did improve
with model size.
That's--
What if you can identify
a simpler problem,
maybe you can run
with less samples.
Yes, exactly.
So if the model--
so this is something
that was probably
seen in the repetitive sampling
and the test-time compute
as well, is to-- if you
have simpler problems,
then it's likely that
you can get coverage
with fewer number of samples.
So you don't have to
go to 1 million samples
every single time.
It's almost like
saying the model does--
more likely to generate
the solution in the search
space of what it outputs.
So it should be easier to sample
or its initial set of solutions
with some iteration, with some
iterative refinement should
be easier to correct, as
opposed to having to generate
a lot of different solutions.
One of the gains that
you get if you generate
a lot of parallel
solutions is that you're
trying to get the model
to provide diversity
in the approaches,
and you're not
trying to get it to fix
what it already output.
What about the question four?
How can we embed reasoning
directly into the model?
OK, let's try out.
Let's see what you already said.
Maybe you can have more
on the training side.
By dealing with
the training side,
you can take all
the comments off.
You've done enough problems
so you know in the second one
how it already feels after, like
the framework of the solution.
Instead of one, you know it's
very probably to the problems
that we mentioned
in that framework.
And that is slightly--
it's slightly different than the
standard of directly for when
solving being the change
or we'll be solving.
We have the final solution and
the bit of the final solution.
So if we don't have
enough common data,
then we use the LLM to
test if there's a code
to see the first
section is about what,
the second section
is about what,
the third section about what.
So it's-- the training data
is that part of the training.
The data is only the
framework, the set
where it's that few
steps with that form
under that pre-training and
that space between the same.
OK.
So what Geoffrey is
saying is that you
add hints in your training data
set around the solution of what
kind of algorithm is being
used to solve the problem.
What's a more generic
version of that?
What have we already covered
in that line of work?
As programmers, you think
before you write the answer.
What if that thinking
could be captured?
If you added those
chain of thought
as part of your training
set or if you remember
the STAR approach where
you're getting the model
to generate the solution and
then give the hint as the answer
and then ask it to come up
with that reasoning, then
that can also be part of how
the model embeds it, right?
Any other ideas?
I think the other interesting
thing that was mentioned,
which is probably
worth highlighting,
is that if you have a more
complex problem than you might
want to decompose the
problem into subparts
and add hints for subparts
as opposed to trying
to solve the problem in one go,
because these are hard problems.
Yes.
It's about what you tackled
that for the standalone
but that's sequential.
Maybe you give-- you succeed on
the first intermediate output,
and you have something
forward that is never going
to make the second part work.
So how does that sequential or
how can you decompose that work?
So I think all of these are
hinting at we do need to close
the loop at some point in a
multi-step fashion and almost
want a tree search style of
solution where you basically
want the--
I basically sample for,
say, the first step,
and is that roughly correct?
And you want to sample
for the second step,
and then you want to
be able to backtrack.
So it's roughly heading
in that direction,
but it's early work
that gives you hints.
So it's basically
got on your thinking,
and then perhaps that's
your project, right?
But your question
is very relevant
as to what happens
if your answer is
correct in the first step,
but then the next step
is not correct?
And the task
decomposition is often
relevant in that most problems
have a certain way of solving.
So if there is common instructed
patterns, then that's doable.
But if you do
expect patterns that
are out of distribution,
then maybe,
you do need human in the loop.
That's like a
scientist style of work
that folks covered last lecture.
OK?
Let's come to the last part.
So we spent a lot
of time on just code
and how to select a
set of code samples
that can pass and solve
competitive coding problems.
Now, let's look at how
would you do something
like building a
deep research agent?
So Search-o1 is basically going
to use large reasoning models
as the base and then try
to build a deep research
agents on top of that.
And it's worth paying
attention because you
will use this in homework 3.
So the key idea here is that
you want to use large reasoning
models to retrieve
based on a query
that you want to give the model.
So large reasoning models
have impressive reasoning,
but as you know that
most of these models
are trained on
with some knowledge
cut off dates, so they
typically will not
have the freshest knowledge.
If something happened
yesterday, the model
will need to go
look up that data.
It's not going to be
there in the model.
The other challenge when you
work with reasoning models, per
se, is that they will go
and output a lot of tokens
in long-form reasoning, but
when they have knowledge gaps,
they will be using terms that
are expressing uncertainty.
So one example is that if you go
use benchmark on GPQA data set,
you will see the term perhaps
in the reasoning chains a lot,
or you will see the term
alternatively or wait or--
so they're basically
expressing that the knowledge
gaps will show up as uncertainty
in the way the model is
thinking.
So you want to bootstrap
that in some way,
because otherwise,
those knowledge
gaps will continue to propagate
through the entire reasoning
chain.
Now, one simple solution based
on learning from feedback
or learning from tool
calls is that why don't we
just take this query and
get a relevant document?
So you take this query,
pass it to a search tool,
and get the relevant
document, and then
put that document in the prompt,
and then get the model to output
based on that.
Why is that not enough?
So that would be more like
retrieval augmented generation.
So whatever is your question,
you generate a query,
and you get a document, and
you put it in the prompt,
and then that's what you
use to retrieve the answer.
Now, the challenge with
that sort of simple approach
is that you retrieve
once at the beginning.
So you don't have the
ability to tweak things.
And it's possible that
if your search problem is
complex enough, then
each reasoning step
will need different
pieces of information.
So if you have a problem, which
is asking just the weather,
then maybe a single
search call is enough,
but if you're asking to solve
a complex problem, which
has multiple parts
to solving it,
then after it gets through a
certain amount of reasoning,
it needs to go look up
additional information.
So for complex reasoning, it's
extremely hard to get it right,
and same for
multi-step reasoning.
So typically,
retrieval augmented
generation will improve--
will show improvement
over direct reasoning,
but in multi-step reasoning,
it definitely suffers.
So the solution that
Search-o1 proposes
is that the model generates
the queries on the go.
So whenever it sees
these knowledge gaps,
it will trigger a query.
It will generate a
search query of what
tool calls to generate
and go search things over.
And there will be
multiple iterations
in a single reasoning session of
like fetching these documents.
And the second thing
it will do differently,
and I will show
examples of that,
is that it will analyze
the retrieved documents.
So instead of just dumping what
it retrieved as the document,
it will analyze the
retrieved document
and extract relevant chunks
of information from there.
And it will only put
these relevant information
into the prompts so
that it integrates well
into the reasoning chain.
So just to reiterate
how this works--
so this is an original
question, which
is a chemistry question,
which is talking about--
it wants to get the carbon
atoms count of product 3
which is output of a bunch of
different chemical reactions.
So if you were to use a
large reasoning model,
you would ask the model
to start thinking.
It looks at this term,
which I don't understand,
and perhaps the model
doesn't understand.
So it will go ask a
lookup, what does it mean?
Now, one trick is that
it doesn't go look up,
so it makes a guess and
comes up with whatever
is in its knowledge base
in the stored weights
and provides a final answer
based on what it guessed.
But if there is a guess here,
and it got the answer wrong,
then those things
will cascade as errors
into whatever is
the final answer.
So all the perhaps or
all the uncertainty
will basically cascade
into the final answer.
So your certainty for
the final answer is low.
Now, one possibility
is that you basically--
whenever you encounter
unfamiliar knowledge,
you can now do web searches.
So that would be
a simple scenario
of like OK, unfamiliar
term, basically go and do
a tool call for search, return
the document that basically
has that search tool for perhaps
there is a Wikipedia page,
or there's a web page
that has that information,
and put that in the reasoning
chain, and now do the--
put that in the prompt, and
then do the call again, and then
provide the final
answer based on that.
The only challenge with this
is that as you basically
increase your amount of
content you're putting there,
there might be not as
much relevant content
in these documents.
Like if you went and fetched
like 10 documents that
were related to the
information, there's
too much information for
the model to process,
so it might actually not
still give the correct answer.
So in this particular case,
it was like 10 carbon atoms
in product 3.
Here's 14 carbon atoms.
So it still got it wrong.
What Search-o1 is proposing
is that now you have--
whenever you get the
unfamiliar knowledge,
it will go and search
for helpful information.
So that's still a tool
call to your search.
But then, it will reason
within the document.
So it will try to look
at these documents
and see if this is helpful
information or not,
extract the relevant
content, and then put it back
in the next prompt, like
what is the relevant chunk
of information to put?
And that will allow the model
to continue coherent reasoning
and provide the
final answer here.
So in this particular
case, basically,
the ability to do this
summarization of information
or reason within the
document really improves
the quality of life, how it
gets to the final answer instead
of clustering the prompt with
10 documents or 20 documents.
Questions on what's
the difference
between the three approaches?
Yes.
Why in the final leg there
does it say-- in the first one,
it says--
or perhaps, it may look at
as far as this little one.
Does it concern you?
Because it's been
given the information.
So the uncertainty has reduced.
It has actually been-- it's not
even saying that in the middle
one, which--
because it's been given the
right information in the prompt.
I think the harder part is, how
does it know what to search for?
It needs to know which
keywords it does not know.
That's the question I would ask.
It gets to know his answer.
The answer is I
think you basically
need to break down what are the
key-- so there is different ways
to tackle that question, right?
If you're building
a real application,
you want to identify
which parts--
you don't want to rely on the
knowledge base of the LLM.
And you actually do
want to do a tool
call because that
information is likely not
what you want to trust the
weights of the LLM for.
It's almost like you're
finding the key entities
in your question and fetching
information on those.
OK.
So there were two things
that we are covering here.
So one is the Agentic
RAG, and one is Search-o1.
So I'll cover both here.
Let's first understand
Agentic RAG because then,
we build on top of that
in the Search-o1 process.
In Agentic RAG, what you're
doing is you're basically--
every time you are hitting
entities that you care about,
you're basically going to
insert special tokens where you
are going to trigger a search.
And then when you
get that document,
you're going to
insert those results.
So model is generating
some output tokens.
When it's seeing certain amount
of uncertainty in its output
tokens, it's generating
these search queries
between the special tokens.
And based on that, it goes
and does the tool call.
And the retrieval
tool will essentially
return those documents,
which will then be inserted
into the reasoning chain.
So this is happening in
large reasoning models
as part of the whole
reasoning process of like,
it's also calling tools as
part of the reasoning process.
So that's one way to solve it.
But the documents
can be lengthy,
and they can contain noise.
And oftentimes,
depending on how good
the long-context understanding
and reasoning of the model is,
they might-- actually, if
you put 10 or 20 documents,
it might actually not be able
to do a good job at reasoning
over them.
So the reason in documents
module of Search-o1
will allow you to do analysis
of each of the documents of how
relevant the content
is, and then it
considers the current query,
what it was reasoning previously
plus this chunk of information
that it extracted, and appends
that to the prompt to
allow the model to continue
reasoning based on that.
So it's essentially
a multi-step process
within that retrieval
tool function itself
because it's basically getting
that document information,
but then also doing
an extraction process
on top of that.
It's as almost as humans.
You don't want to
just go and curate
all the possible references.
You also want to take
notes on those references
so that you have some way of
doing a better job understanding
and synthesizing
that information.
And this allows the model to
do a better job at reasoning
when we are adding
external knowledge.
And especially for
complex queries,
this becomes quite important.
Yes.
How is it pausing
previous reasoning?
And if there's any
corrections needed
for the previous reasoning,
how does it handle corrections?
So there is an assumption
that there is a state
or there is a memory
buffer that's keeping that.
It's not obvious in the
way this is structured,
but there is basically
some form of notion of this
is the search query
I'm trying to answer
and some buffer of where is the
previous reasoning and so on.
All of it in the slide.
Yeah.
Yes.
[INAUDIBLE] to prepare some new
form in the Agentic RAG module.
On top of that, we just ask
the model to do some summation
and then it continues reasoning.
So is that directly transferred
to the second style like--
I mean, does this
directly mix method
to be the new method
proposed when it's due?
Say that part again, or you
can just speak up louder.
I mean, if you just modify
the prompt in the Agentic RAG
module, like you ask the
model to do some summation
and then continue the
reasoning, does that
produce the same result
on recent models?
So I think that's
a great question.
And I would encourage you
folks to actually try that out
in homework 3.
I think the assumption
there is that if you
were to issue that prompt, you
are assuming that the context
length of the model and the
reasoning over that context
length is working really well.
This is basically Agentic
Context Engineering-style paper.
So it's basically-- there's a
recent paper called "Agentic
Context Engineering."
So essentially,
the limitation here
is coming from what can
you put in context length
that the model is going to
do a really good job at.
In ideal world, we
would want that.
That's where we want to shoot.
And hopefully, by the end of the
year, that's where we will be.
OK.
So let's look at the example.
So we were covering this
example of carbon atom
count in product 3 based on
a bunch of different chemical
reactions.
In vanilla reasoning,
the challenge
was that it was
guessing the structure.
So it definitely
got wrong answer.
In Agentic RAG, because you were
just retrieving the documents,
they ended up being too lengthy,
so it did disrupt the reasoning.
In Search-o1 process,
it did search
for this particular
formula, and then
it refined it to a
certain structure,
and then that integrated
cleanly into reasoning.
So essentially, the notion of
extracting the right information
from the documents
really helps Search-o1
and get to the correct answer
in this particular case.
Now, if you were to
go beyond the example
to results, what we're plotting
is different domains, physics,
chemistry, biology, and overall.
And you're plotting
pass at 1 on the y-axis,
and then you're plotting
the number of documents
that you get on x-axis.
So typically, as you increase
the number of documents,
for direct reasoning
and for RAG,
the accuracy does not go up.
But in this particular
case, as you
increase the number
of documents,
you are actually able to do
better because you can summarize
what is relevant information or
not, in this particular case,
assuming that the documents--
fetching more documents
gives you more relevant
information related
to the problem that
you're solving.
So this is basically
another axes of--
instead of doing
iterative refinement,
you can do parallel refinement
because you can basically
go fetch more information
and then chunk it down
to put it in the model context.
Now, if you were to compare the
performance on GPQA data set--
so if you just compared GPQA
data set in physics, chemistry,
and biology--
I was showing you a
plot in the last slide--
human experts in physics,
chemistry, and biology on GPQA
would score this much.
If you look at the reasoning
models and you build Search-o1
and on top of them, what
you notice is that--
for example, in
physics and chemistry,
Search-o1 actually is quite
competitive, sometimes
even better than what
human experts would do.
These are hard
problems, by the way.
And in biology, it's
almost competitive
to say the biology is
solving the problem.
One comment I want
to make is that you
want to focus on physicists
solving physics problems.
So you want to focus
on the diagonal here.
It's maybe not obvious like
if you change the domain then.
That's the number
you're comparing to.
So the Search-o1 is
doing pretty well
in physics here and in biology
here, and in chemistry,
not so much.
[INAUDIBLE] this Search-o1
perform even better
than most physicists do this.
So what's the level
of this physicists?
[CHUCKLES]
Maybe they didn't do a good
job sourcing the physicists.
I think we're definitely
getting to a point
where the models are able to
do well in certain domains
more than the--
but this is not
to say that you're
outperforming human experts.
It's more to say that
you're competitive
with the human experts for
this class of problems, yeah.
So there's still a lot
of headroom in chemistry.
[CHUCKLES]
Yes.
I have a question
for the chemistry.
You've seen a lot even
all this chemistry
like the-- what's so fetching we
should-- chemistry formula can
be wrong.
I'm just wondering whether it
performed worse in the chemistry
just because the chemistry
part, how to organize it
is complicated.
You want to preserve the meaning
of some population, but you--
I mean, you can't
just change one thing.
The pop on chemistry,
like the behavior
may change dramatically.
So I'm just wondering whether
it's just because-- how do you
better preserve part of the--
how to render it hopeless,
I say, it's not popular.
It might be.
I will let you actually
go try to evaluate on GPQA
and see if the
chemistry segment--
if that hypothesis applies.
It is possible.
I mean, in every subject, when
you go and from these models,
the level of expertise
varies for different reasons.
It's also possible the training
data set was not that strong.
So it's out of distribution.
And the other comment that I
was making earlier, if you--
basically, as you increase
the number of documents--
This particular technique
is able to leverage the fact
that as you increase
the number of documents,
you can improve the performance
just because you're not just
making the context longer.
You're actually providing
relevant context
from each of those documents.
The other big thing
that I want to highlight
is that in multi-hop
question answering,
this is particularly relevant
because in multi-hop question
answering, you do tend to
hit some amount of saturation
in terms of performance
with standard RAG.
And even with
Agentic RAG, you do
tend to hit some
amount of saturation.
So in HotpotQA,
in 2Wiki, MusiQue,
or Bamboogle for example, if
you just did RAG, for example,
you would not hit the
state-of-the-art numbers.
But with Search-o1, in
a lot of these cases,
you are hitting the
highest numbers.
The bolded numbers across
that particular line
are coming from
Search-o1 as a process.
So it is providing
a lot of value,
even in the multi-hop
question answering
across multiple documents.
Yes.
[INAUDIBLE]
What are the precision and
recall in the retrieval system?
That's a great question.
Why did the-- precision
is the-- or the retrieval
itself is above
it, not the model.
So I think there is
an assumption here
that you did draw at least
for the way I am explaining.
I mean, it's possible that
you didn't retrieve the right
documents, but if you look
at the set of questions,
I think the main claim that this
paper is making is that if you
find multiple relevant documents
that are loosely correlated
to what you're querying
about, even then,
once you put all of those
documents in the context line,
then that's--
you're asking the model to do
a lot in terms of reasoning
over that many documents.
So that's the claim that this
particular paper is making.
So in terms of if you were to
look at the takeaways here,
the gains are definitely
coming from the fact
that it's able to
reduce the uncertainty.
And the document quality or what
you basically refine knowledge,
both of those improve.
And in the multi-turn scenario,
once you can figure out
what you don't know it's
able to-- even after refining
across documents, it can
do this iterative loop
of improving upon that.
So it can construct
better searches
over multi-turn scenarios.
So in this particular
case, the reasoning quality
improves substantially
because you're
providing more
relevant documents,
and then you're
also figuring out
where the uncertainty
is over multiple steps.
So effectively, you have
the right documents.
And then you can
correct yourself
because when you put the
documents in there, if you're
still seeing uncertainty, then
you have additional searches
to go for.
So there were some
numbers that the paper
gives of the number of
perhaps or wait or likely.
Basically, anything that
quantifies uncertainty
in the reasoning chains
goes down substantially
in this particular approach.
So they're basically
analyzing the reasoning chains
of the model.
So just to summarize
what we covered
here is that when we are
building doing deep research
agents on top of, say, the
large reasoning models, that's
a very effective way
to bridge the knowledge
gaps that exist in
large language models.
But just doing simple
retrieval augmented
generation is often not enough.
And even with just fetching
the documents, using tool calls
is not enough.
You need to be able to do that
effectively over multiple turns,
and then identify the
relevant information to refine
which set of documents to keep.
So the large reasoning
models by themselves
often don't do a
good job in scaling
well if you put a lot
of documents in there.
So this particular approach
allows you to improve on that.
And larger models
often do better.
And then-- OK, there's another
paper that I wanted to cover,
but I didn't end up covering.
So the Search-R1
stuff effectively
varies from Search-o1 in that
it teaches the model how to go
search in an automatic way.
So what I wanted to say here was
that Search-R1 versus Search-o1.
Search-o1 is closing the loop
with a prompting-based approach.
Search-R1 can actually
teach the model
to do this with a reinforcement
learning-based loop.
We will not cover
this paper today
because we are
basically at the end,
but it's worth going and
taking a look at that paper.
Questions?
Yes.
I was just following this
poster during the definition
of a language model.
So when we generate
an answer, are we
supposed to have
the ability to put
a probability of that answer?
And I'm just wondering
that when we have this,
let's say 1,000 generations,
each generation have a different
probability, or at
least in some extent.
And has there been
some correlation
between the right answers and
the probabilities, or they are--
by definition, they are
also a bit uncorrelated.
And also, same question to
RAG, there's got to be--
I have a RAG
augmented generation.
I can imagine that
some of the-- maybe it
messes up some of
the definition.
Is there any difference in
the probability of the answer?
I mean, that's a great
experiment to go do.
So let me answer
the first question.
And the second
question, you will
have to go experiment yourself.
So in the first question,
typically-- so there's
a lot of studies, but if you
were to just take the output
generation and compute the log
probabilities of the output
tokens and aggregate them
in some meaningful way,
not just sum them,
you'll have to do
some averaging or some
geometric product or something.
What you'll find is that the
models tend to be overconfident
about what they--
overconfident, so if you
were to calibrate that
to the right
answer, often you'll
find that the correctness is--
Like if it's 50% correct, it
will still be overconfident.
It'll be like 80% very
confident that this is correct.
And this shows up
in the ways in which
if you try to correct
the model outputs,
it will sometimes be
pretty strong in like, no,
this is the right answer and
will not change its mind.
So in some ways, the
model outputs do tend--
have exhibited not
high calibration
and are more on the
overconfident side.
And there have been
research to try
to get the model to
estimate the confidence, say
in a second pass or in a--
and try to do RL or RLHF on
top of that to get the model
to calibrate and do things
so that it doesn't actually
emit answers that it
has low confidence over.
So there has definitely been
efforts in that direction.
Different models exhibit
different behaviors.
We don't know
which lab did what.
So we just get these notions of
oh, the model is hallucinating.
There is no correlation between
the actual right answer both
from the 1,000 and the--
I think there is a
correlation in that
if the answer is correct,
then the model will likely
get it correct.
But if the answer is
incorrect, the model
might be overconfident
in feeling
that it knows the answer.
That's been the
observed pattern,
but I think this
is worth studying.
The hallucinations
in just the ability
of the model to
know what they know
is an active area of research.
And it's actually a great
set of research projects
if someone wants to pursue it.